Elijah Raffo

Portland, OR 97224

- (971) 275-7057
- eliraffo@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/eliraffo
- eliraffo.github.io

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

An operations specialist and data analyst with a passion for delivering business impact. Has experience working within a fast-paced environment, building and leading a team, being a specialist in business operations, analyzing large datasets, being a self-starter, and problem solving.

EDUCATION

University of Oregon • Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Major Concentration • Operations and Business Analytics

Minor

■ Computer Information Technology

Course Concepts: Supply Chain Management ● Regression Analysis ● Demand Forecasting ● Predictive Analytics ● Database Management

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Analyst

Lane Forest Products, Inc. • Eugene, OR

June 2018 - June 2019

Sept. 2015 - June 2019

GPA: 3.60 / 4.0

General Responsibilities:

Operated as the inventory control specialist of a logistic reload which over 6 months moved 55,000 tons of material.

Partnered with the database manager to validate data integrity, and automate an extract, transform, and load process.

Operated as the export specialist for international orders by managing documentation, accounts payable/receivable, and movement of material.

Created procedures and flowcharts which enabled the whole department to fulfill international export orders.

Measured KPI's by performing queries, data analysis, and data visualization to answer stakeholder questions regarding business operations.

Reported to senior management weekly on material sent to an agricultural customer to inform the delivery schedule.

<u>Improved</u> multiple functional areas by automating and improving spreadsheets.

Worked with the Offsite Production Supervisor to implement improved monthly reporting, contract generation, and offsite scheduling.

Analytic Projects:

<u>Conducted</u> an analysis of the Delivery Department by developing a cost model. Implemented a delivery pricing structure which identified and stopped losses on delivery, and increased profit by \$36,000:

- Created visual models for stakeholders which intuitively explained the profit margin of all order combinations (~50,000 combinations).
- Designed a spreadsheet which uses a Google Distance API to optimize the delivery price quoted to customers.

Supply Logistics Intern

Townshend's Tea Company ● Portland, OR

June 2017 – September 2017

<u>Implemented</u> a redesigned Point-of-Sale interface at all Eugene Teahouse locations which helped:

Improve storefront efficiency, and created data which could measure customer preferences, inventory levels, and reorder points.

HIGHLIGHTED SKILLS

Beginner

SAP ● Python | Pandas, NumPy ● VBA & Macros ● JavaScript | RESTful API's, Node.js, React.js ● Google Analytics ● SPSS

Intermediate

MS Excel | Pivot Tables, Dashboards, Solver ● Tableau ● SQL ● MS Office | Visio, Access, Outlook, PowerPoint, Word

PROJECTS AND CERTIFICATES

Emerald Kalama Chemical - Fragrance & Flavor Optimization • Project

Partnered with a global chemical company to build a model which optimizes their product mix and models their unique production constraints.

Wine Classification ● Project

Using python, developed machine learning models like SVM, k-NN, and Forest Tree to classify the quality of a wine (up to an 85% accuracy).

Video Game Database ● Project

Produced an ER diagram, a relational schema, queries, and database built to the second normal form to answer consumer questions.

Certificate of Outdoor Leadership ● 600 Hours of Training and Application

Over 3 years, developing interpersonal and leadership skills in the backcountry. Applied these lessons as an assistant leader in university classes taught by the Outdoor Pursuits Program. Classes included leading groups of six on three-day backcountry outings in the snow and rain, completing a Wilderness First Responder Certificate, teaching outdoor rock-climbing safety, and teaching vertical rescue techniques.